让我们总结一下我们从获取图像中学到的一些关键事项
Let’s summarise some of the key things that we have learned about getting images from
将世界变成一台可以用MATLAB操作它们的计算机。
the world into a computer where we can manipulate them with MATLAB.
我们已经查看了一些关于如何从文件加载图像的示例;加载图片
We have looked at a number of examples about how we can load images from a file; load images
住在相机旁;从其他人的相机加载图像，连接到网络摄像头
live from a camera; load images from somebody else’s camera, a web camera attached to
这个星球上的某个地方;如何从电影文件加载帧我们可以
the internet somewhere on the planet; how to load frames from a movie file and we can
甚至从谷歌地球等在线互联网服务中加载帧。
even load frames from an online internet service like Google Earth.
您将注意到所有这些不同的方法是有一些共同的模式
What you will notice about all of these different approaches is that there’s some common patterns
这里。我们创建一个可能是摄像机对象或轴的图像源对象
here. We create an image source object that might be a video camera object or an Axis
网络摄像头对象或电影对象，然后我们使用该对象的方法之一，
web camera object or movie object and then we use one of the methods of that object,
抓取方法，从该图像源获取下一个图像。所以我们能够
the grab method, to obtain the next image from that image source. So we are able to
使用仅变化非常非常的软件来抓取图像的各种图像源
grab images a diversity of image sources, using software which varies only very, very
小。现在我们将图像放入MATLAB中
little. Now once we have the image into the MATLAB
环境由矩阵表示;通过矩形数组。每个元素
environment it is represented by a matrix; by a rectangular array of numbers. Every element
在该数组中表示在该对应点的光强度
within that array represents the intensity of light at the corresponding point in the
真实世界。我们将这些元素称为图片元素，
real world. We refer to these elements as picture elements,
通常缩小为像素。像素的位置由两个坐标定义。
which is often contracted to pixel. The position of a pixel is defined by two coordinates.
由符号u表示的水平坐标是距左手的距离
The horizontal coordinate which I denote by the symbol u, is the distance from the left-hand
边缘和我用符号v定义的垂直坐标定义为
edge, and the vertical coordinate which I define by the symbol v, is defined as the
距离左上角的距离。MATLAB是一个计算环境
distance from the top left-hand corner. MATLAB is a computational environment for
处理矩阵，矩阵的约定是我们用它来索引它们
dealing with matrices, and the convention for matrices is that we index them using the
行索引首先跟着列索引。现在行是垂直坐标和
row index first followed by the column index. Now the row is the vertical coordinate and
列是水平坐标。所以在正常方式之间有一个翻转
the column is the horizontal coordinate. So there is a flip here between the normal way
我们表示矩形框架或图形中的坐标。通常我们会参考
that we represent the coordinates in a rectangular frame or in a graph. Normally we would reference
水平坐标后跟垂直坐标-我们会写u，vas
the horizontal coordinate followed by the vertical coordinate—we would write u,v as
像素的坐标。在MATLAB中，因为我们要索引到矩阵，所以我们必须反转
the coordinate of a pixel. In MATLAB, because we are indexing into a matrix we have to reverse
所以我们会写v，你。现在这令人困惑，这有点像
that so we would write v,u. Now this is confusing and it is a bit of a
陷阱刚刚开始的人。记住那个非常重要
trap for people who are just starting out. It is really important to remember that the
索引矩阵时的坐标与坐标相比是反转的
coordinates when you are indexing a matrix are reversed compared to the coordinates that
当你想到一个二维平面时，你会用。
you would use when you think about a two dimensional plane.